{
  "reference_number": "5336",
  "clauses": [
    {
      "question": "1. What process should the Government use to set a new emissions reduction target in legislation?",
      "question_index": 0,
      "answer": "The Government sets a 2050 target in legislation now",
      "answer_index": 0,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "2. If the Government sets a 2050 target now, which is the best target for New Zealand?",
      "question_index": 1,
      "answer": "Net Zero Carbon Dioxide - Reducing net carbon dioxide emissions to zero by 2050",
      "answer_index": 13,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "3. How should New Zealand meet its targets?",
      "question_index": 2,
      "answer": "Domestic emissions reductions only (including from new forest planting)",
      "answer_index": 7,
      "notes": "Reduce the national speed limit."
    },
    {
      "question": "4. Should the Zero Carbon Bill allow the 2050 target to be revised if circumstances change?",
      "question_index": 3,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "5. The Government proposes that three emissions budgets of five years each (i.e. covering the next 15 years) be in place at any given time. Do you agree with this proposal?",
      "question_index": 15,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "6. Should the Government be able to alter the last emissions budget (i.e. furthest into the future)?",
      "question_index": 4,
      "answer": "No - emissions budgets should not be able to be changed",
      "answer_index": 9,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "7. Should the Government have the ability to review and adjust the second emissions budget within a specific range under exceptional circumstances? See p36 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 5,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "8. Do you agree with the considerations we propose that the Government and the Climate Change Commission take into account when advising on and setting budgets? See p44 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 6,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": "Do not make exceptions for the poor. The poor will always be disproportionally disadvantaged - it's not something that's going to be\nremedied. Socialism will always fail as it has everywhere it's been tried."
    },
    {
      "question": "9. Should the Zero Carbon Bill require Governments to set out plans within a certain timeframe to achieve the emissions budgets?",
      "question_index": 7,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "10. What are the most important issues for the Government to consider in setting plans to meet budgets? For example, who do we need to work with, what else needs to be considered?",
      "question_index": 8,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "Food production obviously takes advantage over transportation. Home gardening should be encouraged."
    },
    {
      "question": "11. The Government has proposed that the Climate Change Commission advises on and monitors New Zealand's progress towards its goals. Do you agree with these functions? See p42 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 9,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "12. What role do you think the Climate Change Commission should have in relation to the New Zealand Emissions Trading Scheme (NZ ETS)?",
      "question_index": 10,
      "answer": "Advising the Government on policy settings in the NZ ETS",
      "answer_index": 6,
      "notes": "Except that no politician will commit political suicide to do what's necessary when the SHTF event may occur after their office tenure."
    },
    {
      "question": "13. The Government has proposed that Climate Change Commissioners need to have a range of essential and desirable expertise. Do you agree with the proposed expertise? See p45 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 11,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "For the most part... but social considerations should not be a major concern."
    },
    {
      "question": "14. Do you think the Zero Carbon Bill should cover adapting to climate change?",
      "question_index": 12,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "Most proposals (like this one) consider sea-level rise, but the greater dangers will likely be the change in food growing regions and\n\nseasons, and the availability of fresh water. We need more small farmers and fewer lawyers and bankers."
    },
    {
      "question": "16. Should we explore setting up a targeted adaptation reporting power that could see some organisations share information on their exposure to climate change risks?",
      "question_index": 14,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "Do you have any other comments you'd like to make?",
      "question_index": 16,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "If the government is serious about reducing our CO2 emissions, they'll begin by dropping the national speed limit, perhaps to 80 (the\nUSA dropped to 90 during the oil-embargo). Energy required to maintain a velocity is quadratic with speed, so lower speeds should\n\nconserve significant fuel and allow for smaller and lighter commute vehicles to operate safely. Cargo should be sent via rail or cargo\nship and not over expensive roadways (road damage is exponential with the weight of the vehicle - and we used to have a law about\n\nthis very thing.) Carpooling should be encouraged - and since we know where and when everyone goes (thanks to their cellular\nphone automatic registration messages), the government could encourage those who travel in parallel to join together for their\ncommute. Working from home should also be encouraged. Diesel Road User Charges should be added at the fuel pump, so those\n\ninefficient vehicles actually pay their fair share relative to those diesel vehicles that are more economical - leaving it as it is adds an\nunnecessary overhead (purchasing the RUC) and gives heavy vehicles that damage the roads no incentive to improve their efficiency.\n\nI have many such ideas, and I'm not seeing much of these ideas discussed anywhere. But perhaps it's because I don't watch TV and\nthe broadcast radio sucks."
    }
  ]
}
